A Guide to the McHone Brothers (LLC) Collection of Houck Tannery Records, 1870-1913: SC 0172
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
McHone Brothers (LLC) Collection of Houck Tannery Records,
1870-1913
Special Collections, James Madison University
Houck Tannery
SC 0172
6.7 cubic feet; 8 boxes
This collection consists of 6.7 cubic feet of records documenting the operations of the Houck Tannery and the J.P. Houck Store in Harrisonburg, Virginia, from 1870-1913, chiefly from 1890 to 1913. The collection contains account ledgers, registries, correspondence, and financial and transportation documents that record this turn of the century industry.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research. Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection. Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the James Madison University Special Collections Library to use this collection.
Acquisition Information
Records were donated by the present building owner, McHone Brothers, LLC, in 2000. The collection was discovered in the late 1990s during renovations to the Houck Building on Court Square (71 South Main) in downtown Harrisonburg, the former offices of the Houck Tannery and store.
Bio/Historical Note
Joseph P. Houck was born on April 4, 1839, in Allentown, Pennsylvania. In the spring of 1866 he went to work for Shenandoah Iron Works in Page County, Virginia. He was successful in the business for fourteen years. Around 1880, Houck and his family moved to Harrisonburg, Virginia, as he had significant business interests there. He had bought a controlling share of the Harrisonburg Steam Tannery in 1878, which soon was renamed the Houck Tannery. In 1879 he opened the Houck Store near Court Square which sold leather goods in addition to household goods and furnishings. Houck was a prominent member of the community, a member of the Rockingham Union Lodge, and secretary and treasurer of Valley Telephone. He died on June 16, 1908. Both the Tannery and the Store were passed on to his son, Joe (J.T.). The younger Houck sold the store to William B. Dutrow in 1913, but continued to own and operate the tannery until its close in the 1920s.
The tannery which came to be known as the Houck Tannery had a long history prior to its ownership by J.P. Houck. Local historian John Wayland noted in his 1949 book Historic Harrisonburg that sources indicate that as far back 1826, Joseph Cline had "carried on the tanyard now owned by Lowenback," and that George Conrad had later purchased Cline's "farm & the tanyard in town," although the date of that sale is not provided. Nonetheless, in 1871 J.A. Loewenbach owned and operated the tannery. That year, he constructed a new building for providing steam power, and in 1872 he had run a pipe from an unidentified spring in town to the tannery.
By 1878 ownership of the tannery was transferred to J.P. Houck. Although several tanneries operated in Rockingham County, Houck's was the largest. An 1880 census reports a capital investment of $75,000 and thirty employees in the tannery. The industry also supported significant numbers of workers who supplied and transported raw materials to the factory. A spur was laid from the Chesapeake and Western Railroad directly to the tannery warehouse to facilitate the tonnage of bark required for the manufacture of leather. In 1889 the tannery boasted a well that ran 600 feet deep. In addition, the tannery's powerful steam plant is credited with being the first provider of electricity in Harrisonburg. The city contracted with Houck in 1890 to power its street lights prior to the formation of the Harrisonburg Electric Commission. The factory ceased operation in the 1920s, and its 120 foot smokestack was demolished in 1929. A municipal parking deck now stands on the site. The sole remaining structure housed Whitesel-Sinton farm equipment in the 1930s, the armory until the 1950s, and the police department until its demolition in the early 1970s.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of 6.7 cubic feet of records that document the daily purchases and sales of the Houck Tannery and the J.P. Houck Store in Harrisonburg, Virginia, from 1870-1913, chiefly from 1890 to 1913. The collection is arranged in five series: Account Ledgers and Registries, Communication, Financial Documents, Distribution/Transportation Documents, Images, and J.P. Houck Store. The first four series deal primarily with the Tannery; materials relating to the Store are housed in series five. References to the Tannery may be abbreviated JPHTC, while the Houck Store may be abbreviated JPHS.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in five series:
Series 1: Account Ledgers and Registries, 1870-1895
Series 2: Communication, 1900-1912
Series 3: Financial Documents, 1891-1912
Series 4: Distribution/Transportation Documents, 1893-1913
Series 5: J. P. Houck Store, 1898-1912
Items within each series are arranged alphabetically by topic or locality, then chronologically. Original pagination retained.
Related Materials
West Virginia Pulp and Paper Company Logging Photographs, 1927-1931, SC 0130, Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University, Harrisonburg, VA.
Bibliography
Barb, Mia, 1991. Tanbark Industry in the Shenandoah Valley, Oral History Interviews, SdArch 4. Carrier Library Special Collections, James Madison University, Harrisonburg, Va.
Bolgiano, Chris. 1999. "Tanbark Harvesting as an Economic and Environmental Factor in Appalachia." [S.1.:s.n.], 1999. Presented at [the] Shenandoah Valley Regional Studies Seminar, James Madison University, Harrisonburg, Va., January 22, 1999.
Coakley, Sherry L. 1991. "The Old Tannery." Harrisonburg Rockingham Historical Society Newsletter 13(1): 1-2.
"History of Rockingham—Houck Tannery." Daily News-Record, 28 February 1959.
Lathrop, J.M. An Atlas of Shenandoah and Page Counties, Virginia; from actual surveys by J.M. Lathrop and B.N. Griffing. Strasburg, Va.: GP Hammond Pub., 1991. Originally published as: Philadelphia, Pa.: D.J. Lake & Co., 1885.
"Mr. Dutrow's 20th Anniversary." Harrisonburg Daily News, 11 March 1908.
Price, C.G. Sr. "My Recollections of Harrisonburg at the turn of the century." Rockingham Recorder III:1, April 1979.
"Dutrow Buys Houck Store." Daily News-Record, 11 July 1913.
Suter, Scott Hamilton, and Cheryl Lyon. Images of America: Harrisonburg. Chicago: Arcadia Press, 2003.
Suter, Scott Hamilton, and Cheryl Lyon. Places, Faces & Traces: Historical Photographs of Harrisonburg and Rockingham County. Dayton, Va.: Silver Lake Mill, 2005.
Wayland, John W. Historic Harrisonburg. Staunton, Va.: McClure Print. Co., 1949.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Houck Tannery (Harrisonburg, Va.); J.P. Houck Store (Harrisonburg, Va.); Leather industry and trade -- United States; Leather industry and trade -- Virginia -- Rockingham County; Tanning -- United States; Tanning -- Shenandoah River Valley (Va. and W. Va.); Tanning -- Virginia -- Rockingham County; Tanbark -- Transportation -- Southern States -- Sources; Tanneries -- Shenandoah River Valley (Va. and W. Va.); Tanneries -- Virginia -- Rockingham County; Railroads -- Southern States -- History -- Sources; Railroads -- Virginia -- History -- Sources; Industries -- United States -- History; Shenandoah River Valley (Va. and W. Va.) -- History -- Sources; Industries -- Shenandoah River Valley (Va. and W. Va.) -- Sources; Shenandoah River Valley (Va. and W. Va.) -- Economic conditions -- Sources; Shenandoah River Valley (Va. and W. Va.) -- Economic conditions -- Statistics; Rockingham County (Va.) -- History -- Sources; Industries -- Virginia -- Rockingham County -- Sources; Industries -- Virginia -- Harrisonburg -- Sources; Voter registration -- Virginia -- Harrisonburg -- Sources; Political participation -- Virginia -- Harrisonburg -- Sources; Voting registers -- Virginia -- Rockingham County; Harrisonburg (Va.) -- History -- Sources; Edinburg (Va.) -- History -- Sources; Stokesville (Va.) -- History -- Sources; Rockingham County (Va.) -- Economic conditions -- Sources
- Series 1: Account Ledgers and Registries, 1870-1895
  Scope and Content
  Series 1, Account Ledgers and Registries, 1870-1895, consists of a bound register (1870-1884), account ledger, and check stub registry. The register lists names alphabetically by race, date registered, and age. Initially presumed to have been an employee register, many of the names listed were prominent local citizens and/or businessmen who were not in the employ of the tannery; therefore it is likely that this was an unofficial voter register that somehow came to be housed in the same building as the tannery records, and may in fact have had nothing to do with the tannery itself.
  - Employee/Contractor Register, 1870-1884 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Transcription of Register (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Account Ledger, September 1892-October 1895 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Check stub registry, June 1890-May 1892 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Series 2: Communication, 1900-1912
  Series 2, Communication, 1900-1912, includes business and payroll correspondence, telegrams and telegraphs, arranged alphabetically by topic, then chronologically. Several of the items in payroll correspondence are undated handwritten notes from employees or contract laborers, requesting that their pay be sent home with another individual.
  - Business correspondence, 1901-1912 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Payroll correspondence, From supervisors to Houck, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Payroll correspondence, From supervisors to Houck, February 1901-October 1901 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Payroll correspondence, From supervisors to Houck, May 1902-December 1904 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Payroll correspondence, From supervisors to Houck, January 1905-December 1907 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Payroll correspondence, From supervisors to Houck, 1908-1911, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Payroll correspondence, From employees, December 1901-August 1905 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Payroll correspondence, From employees, 1906-1907 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Payroll correspondence, From employees, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Payroll correspondence, From employees, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Payroll correspondence, From employees, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Payroll correspondence, From employees, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Payroll correspondence, From employees, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Payroll correspondence, From employees, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Telegrams and telegraphs, September 1900-June 9, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Series 3: Financial Documents, 1891-1912
  Series 3, Financial Documents, 1891-1912, is largely composed of receipts and paperwork regarding transactions and regular operating expenses, arranged alphabetically by topic, then chronologically. Topics include cash accounts, expense accounts, and payroll information for Brandiwine [Brandywine], W.V., insurance and utility payments, tax and legal issues, cancelled checks, tannery receipts and vouchers, money orders (from Southern Express & Adams Express) and Houck Store receipts. Oversized materials that have been placed in an oversized box are noted in the contents list.
  - Canceled checks, 1891-1908, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Cash account tabulations, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Cash account tabulations, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Cash account tabulations, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Cash account tabulations, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Cash account tabulations, 1912, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Cash accounts, Brandywine, West Virginia, October 1902-December 1902 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Cash accounts, Brandywine, West Virginia, January 1903-April 1903 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Cash accounts, Brandywine, West Virginia, May 1903-December 1903 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Cash accounts, Brandywine, West Virginia, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Cash accounts, Brandywine, West Virginia, January 1905-September 1905 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Collection Vouchers, Stiegel Lumber Co, June 1903, May-July 1906 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Expense accounts, Brandywine, July 1900-December 1901 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Expense accounts, Brandywine, Expense accounts, Brandywine, January 1902-October 1902 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Money orders, January 1903-December 1909 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Insurance premium statements, 1902-1913 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Legal documents and tax receipts, December 24, 1894-June 12, 1908 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Payroll information, Brandywine, West Virginia, March 1903-December 1903 (Box OV 1, Folder 2)
  - Payroll information, Brandywine, West Virginia, January 1904-March 1905 (Box OV 1, Folder 3)
  - Payroll information, Brandywine, West Virginia, October 1902-September 1905 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Promissory notes, JPHTC owed to others, June 1891-July 1898 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Promissory notes, JPHTC owed to others, August 1898-July 1905 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Promissory notes, JPHTC owed to self, October 29, 1900-April 1, 1908, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - General receipts, bought of JPHS by JPHTC, September 1903-June 1906 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - General receipts, received of JPHTC, August 1900-1901 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - General receipts, received of JPHTC, 1902 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - General receipts, received of JPHTC, 1903 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - General receipts, received of JPHTC, 1904-June 1905, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - General receipts, received of JPHTC, July 1905-1906 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - General receipts, received of JPHTC, 1907-January 1908, June 1911 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - General receipts, leather, 1900-1901 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - General receipts, leather, 1902 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - General receipts, leather, 1903-1904 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - General receipts, leather, 1904-1908 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous notes and receipts, 1892-1900 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous notes and receipts, 1901 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous notes and receipts, 1902 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous notes and receipts, 1903 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous notes and receipts, 1904 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous notes and receipts, 1905 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous notes and receipts, 1906 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous notes and receipts, 1907 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous notes and receipts, 1908-1912 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous notes and receipts, oversize, 1903, undated (Box OV 1, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous notes and receipts, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Post office, 1900-1910 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Utility/rent, October 1900-April 1910 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Vouchers, JPHTC, July 1900-December 1900 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Vouchers, JPHTC, January 1901-May 1901 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Vouchers, JPHTC, June 1901-September 1901 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Vouchers, JPHTC, October 1901-December 1901 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Vouchers, JPHTC, January 1902-March 1902 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Vouchers, JPHTC, April 1902-June 1902 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Vouchers, JPHTC, July 1902-October 1902 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Vouchers, JPHTC, November 1902-December 1902 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Vouchers, JPHTC, January 1903-March 1903 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Vouchers, JPHTC, April 1903-June 1903 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Vouchers, JPHTC, July 1903 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Vouchers, JPHTC, August 1903-September 1903 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Vouchers, JPHTC, October 1903-December 1903 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Vouchers, JPHTC, January 1904-February 1904 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Vouchers, JPHTC, March 1904-April 1904 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Vouchers, JPHTC, May 1904-July 1904 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Vouchers, JPHTC, August 1904-September 1904 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Vouchers, JPHTC, October 1904-December 1904 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Vouchers, JPHTC, January 1905-April 1905 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Vouchers, JPHTC, May 1905-August 1905 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Vouchers, JPHTC, September 1905-October 1905 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Vouchers, JPHTC, November 1905-December 1905 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Vouchers, JPHTC, January 1906-March 1906 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Vouchers, JPHTC, April 1906-June 1906 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Vouchers, JPHTC, July 1906-October 1906 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Vouchers, JPHTC, November 1906-December 1906 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Vouchers, JPHTC, January 1907-March 1907 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Vouchers, JPHTC, April 1907-June 1907 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Vouchers, JPHTC, July 1907-October 1907 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Vouchers, JPHTC, November 1907-December 1907 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Vouchers, JPHTC, January 1908-May 1908 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Vouchers, JPHTC, June 1908-September 1908 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Vouchers, JPHTC, October 1908-December 1908 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Series 4: Distribution and Transportation Documents, 1893-1913
  Series 4, Distribution and Transportation Documents, 1893-1913, constitutes the bulk of the collection and represents regular transactions that occurred during production at the Tannery. These are further divided into eight subseries, based on transaction type. These subseries are arranged alphabetically by location or railway, then chronologically.
  - Freight Bills and Receipts, B&O, 1900-1901 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Freight Bills and Receipts, B&O, 1902 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Freight Bills and Receipts, B&O, 1903 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Freight Bills and Receipts, B&O, 1904 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Freight Bills and Receipts, B&O, 1905-1908 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Freight Bills and Receipts, B&O, Receipts for switching, Agents' receipts, 1906-1907 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Freight Bills and Receipts, B&O, Receipts for switching, April 1905-1906 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Freight Bills and Receipts, B&O, Receipts for switching, 1907 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Freight Bills and Receipts, B&O, Receipts for switching, 1908 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Freight Bills and Receipts, C&W, 1901 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Freight Bills and Receipts, C&W, 1902 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Freight Bills and Receipts, C&W, 1903 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Freight Bills and Receipts, C&W, 1904 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Freight Bills and Receipts, C&W, 1905-April 1906 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Freight Bills and Receipts, C&W, April 1906-December 1906 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Freight Bills and Receipts, C&W, January 1907-June 1907 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Freight Bills and Receipts, C&W, July 1907-December 1907 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Freight Bills and Receipts, C&W, 1908, 1911 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Freight Bills and Receipts, Southern Railway Co., 1898-1900 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Freight Bills and Receipts, Southern Railway Co., 1901 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Freight Bills and Receipts, Southern Railway Co., January 1902-March 1902 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Freight Bills and Receipts, Southern Railway Co., April 1902-September 1902 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Freight Bills and Receipts, Southern Railway Co., October 1902-December 1902 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Freight Bills and Receipts, Southern Railway Co., January 1903-April 1903 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Freight Bills and Receipts, Southern Railway Co., May 1903-October 1903 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Freight Bills and Receipts, Southern Railway Co., November 1903-December 1903 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Freight Bills and Receipts, Southern Railway Co., January 1904-April 1904 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Freight Bills and Receipts, Southern Railway Co., May 1904-August 1904 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Freight Bills and Receipts, Southern Railway Co., September 1904-December 1904 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Freight Bills and Receipts, Southern Railway Co., 1905 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Freight Bills and Receipts, Southern Railway Co., 1906 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Freight Bills and Receipts, Southern Railway Co., 1907 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Freight Bills and Receipts, Southern Railway Co., 1908 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Freight Bills and Receipts, Southern Railway Co., 1909-1913, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Freight Bills and Receipts, Valley Railroad, 1902 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Receipts for Hauling Chestnut Oak Bark by Train Load, Broadway, September 1902-1904 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Receipts for Hauling Chestnut Oak Bark by Train Load, Broadway, 1905-1908 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Receipts for Hauling Chestnut Oak Bark by Train Load, Broadway, February 19090-February 1913 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Receipts for Hauling Chestnut Oak Bark by Train Load, Edinburg, August 1900-1910 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Receipts for Hauling Chestnut Oak Bark by Train Load, Edinburg, 1911-February 1913 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Receipts for Hauling Chestnut Oak Bark by Train Load, Mt. Jackson, August 1900-January 1913 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Receipts for Hauling Chestnut Oak Bark by Train Load, Stokesville, April 1902-September 1903 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Receipts for Hauling Chestnut Oak Bark by Train Load, Stokesville, 1904 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Receipts for Hauling Chestnut Oak Bark by Train Load, Stokesville, 1905 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Receipts for Hauling Chestnut Oak Bark by Train Load, Stokesville, 1906 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Receipts for Hauling Chestnut Oak Bark by Train Load, Stokesville, 1907 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Receipts for Hauling Chestnut Oak Bark by Train Load, Stokesville, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Receipts for Hauling Chestnut Oak Bark by Train Load, Stokesville, 1909 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Receipts for Hauling Chestnut Oak Bark by Train Load, Stokesville, 1910 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Receipts for Hauling Chestnut Oak Bark by Train Load, Stokesville, 1911 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Receipts for Hauling Chestnut Oak Bark by Train Load, Stokesville, 1912-January 1913, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Receipts for Hauling Chestnut Oak Bark by Train Load, Miscellaneous In-State, Aqua-Keezletown (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Receipts for Hauling Chestnut Oak Bark by Train Load, Miscellaneous In-State, Lexington-Spotswood (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Receipts for Hauling Chestnut Oak Bark by Train Load, Miscellaneous In-State, Spring Creek-Woodstock (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Receipts for Hauling Chestnut Oak Bark by Train Load, Out-of-State, unknown (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Receipts for Hauling Chestnut Oak Bark by Wagon Weight, Edinburg, August 1900-May 1901 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Receipts for Hauling Chestnut Oak Bark by Wagon Weight, Harrisonburg, 1900 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Receipts for Hauling Chestnut Oak Bark by Wagon Weight, Harrisonburg, 1901 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Receipts for Hauling Chestnut Oak Bark by Wagon Weight, Harrisonburg, 1902 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Receipts for Hauling Chestnut Oak Bark by Wagon Weight, Harrisonburg, 1903 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Receipts for Hauling Chestnut Oak Bark by Wagon Weight, Harrisonburg, 1904 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Receipts for Hauling Chestnut Oak Bark by Wagon Weight, Harrisonburg, 1905 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Receipts for Hauling Chestnut Oak Bark by Wagon Weight, Harrisonburg, 1906 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Receipts for Hauling Chestnut Oak Bark by Wagon Weight, Harrisonburg, 1907 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Receipts for Hauling Chestnut Oak Bark by Wagon Weight, Harrisonburg, 1908 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Receipts for Hauling Chestnut Oak Extract, 1901-1903 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Receipts for Hauling Chestnut Oak Extract, 1904-1905 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Receipts for Hauling Corn, Hay, etc., 1902-1905 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Reports of bark cars unloaded, September 1903-1906 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Reports of bark cars unloaded, 1907 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Reports of bark cars unloaded, 1908-1909 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Reports of wagon bark received, Broadway, August 1900-December 1900 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Reports of wagon bark received, Edinburg, August 1900-May 1901 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Reports of wagon bark received, Stokesville, June 1902-October 1903, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Reports of wagon bark received, unknown/miscellaneous locations, 1893, undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Time reports, Big River, 1906-1908 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Time reports, Briery Branch, 1906-1908 (Box 7, Folder 16)